Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Hilton Papers, 1969-1979 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Hilton papers 1969-1979 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
1.5 Linear Feet 1050 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Jack Hilton was a radio and management consultant who joined the Public Relations Department of JWT, and held positions of Chief Operating Officer and President of the Telecommunications Division at JWT during the 1970s.
The Jack Hilton Papers cover the years 1969-1979 and contains files primarily relating to Hilton's work in the Public Relations Department of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT). The collection consists of scripts from Hilton's radio program Balance Sheet; quarterly reports from the public relations department of JWT; public relation accounts; correspondence related to personnel and financial issues; a TeleCommunications Development Course; applications to professional organizations; and biographical information including a photograph. Clients mentioned in the papers include Exxon, Ford, Kraft, Mobil Oil, Seven-Up, and Sears. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Hilton Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
1937, June 18 Born, Chicago, Ill.
circa 1955 BS, Northwestern University
1957-1962 News broadcaster, WGN Television, Chicago
1962-1964 News broadcaster, WBBM Radio (CBS), Chicago
1964-1969 News broadcaster, WIND Radio (Group W), Chicago
1969 Manager, Public Relations Department, J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT); elected Vice President, JWT
1970 Director of Public Relations, JWT
1973 Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, JWT; relocated to New York
1974 Joined Overseas Press Club of America, the Pinnacle Club, and the Public Relations Society of America
1975 President, Telecommunications Department, JWT; originated and founded the TeleCommunications Development Course
Jack Hilton's work in radio broadcasting included the show "Balance Sheet." He received several broadcast and management awards, including the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Award. Hilton served on the Blue Ribbon Advisory Committee on Communications for the Secretary of State, Illinois, and was active in the Easter Seal Society, the Multiple Sclerosis Society, and the National Association for Mental Health.
Collection Overview
The Jack Hilton Papers cover the years 1969-1979 and contains files primarily relating to Hilton's work in the Public Relations Department of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT). The collection consists of scripts from Hilton's radio program Balance Sheet; quarterly reports from the public relations department of JWT; public relation accounts; correspondence related to personnel and financial issues; a TeleCommunications Development Course; applications to professional organizations; and biographical information including a photograph. Clients mentioned in the papers include Exxon, Ford, Kraft, Mobil Oil, Seven-Up, and Sears.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hilton, Jack, 1937-
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company -- History
Exxon Company U.S.A.
Ford Motor Company
Kraft Foods Company
Mobil Oil Company
Sears, Roebuck and Company
Seven-Up Company
Advertising agencies.
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- United States -- History
Public relations
Public relations -- History
Public relations -- United States
Public relations consultants
Public relations consultants -- United States
Photographs
Radio scripts
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related material can be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company collections:
Biographical Information
Writings and Speeches
Publications Collection
Loy Baxter Papers
- General Files, 1969-1979 and undated, (3 boxes)
  Includes scripts from Hilton's radio program; quarterly reports from the Public Relations Department of JWT; public relation accounts; correspondence related to personnel and financial issues; the TeleCommunications Development Course; applications to professional organizations; and biographical information.
  Arranged alphabetically
  - Affiliations (Box 1)
    - Overseas Press Club of America, 1974
    - Pinnacle Club, 1974
    - Public Relations Society of America, 1974
  - Balance Sheet scripts, 1978-1979, (4 folders)
  - Barry Farber TV, undated
  - Bette Clemens, undated
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1976-1978, (3 folders)
  - Jack Hilton biographical and photo, undated (Box 2)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturer Association, annual meeting, 1976
  - PR Department, 1969-1973, (1-10 of 14 folders)
    [Arranged quarterly]
  - PR Department, 1972-1973 (continued), (11-14 of 14 folders) (Box 3)
  - Public relations accounts, 1960s-1973, (4 folders)
  - Sears Commentator, 1972 Aug.
  - TeleCommunications Development Course
    - Faculty correspondence, 1977
    - Silver Anvil entry, 1975
    - Solicitation letters, 1977
    - University of Houston, 1975